<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>r on samia.rbind.io</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in r on samia.rbind.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Climate Data: A Tidy Tuesday Project from January 2020 using data from the Australia Wildfires</title>
      <link>/post/australia-wildfires-a-tidy-tuesday-project-from-january-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/australia-wildfires-a-tidy-tuesday-project-from-january-2020/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted on this blog or have worked on a Tidy Tuesday project, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d revisit and post the project I did in January for R4DataScience to visualize climate data during the Australia wildfires earlier this year.
 .center { display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; }  These heatmap visualizations were inspired by Nick Tierny&amp;rsquo;s tutorial on Github transform Australia&amp;rsquo;s Bureau of Meteorology&amp;rsquo;s heatmap data into viridis themed maps and plots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing 75 Years of Measles Incidence Using gganimate: A Tidy Tuesday Project</title>
      <link>/post/making-an-animated-measles-map-a-tidy-tuesday-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-an-animated-measles-map-a-tidy-tuesday-project/</guid>
      <description>For Week 50 of the R4datascience project, I used the provided diseases data mentioned in this SimplyStats blog post. The dataset contains state level data of vaccine preventable infectious diseases over the span of ~70 years.
Packages #packages library(tidyverse) library(gganimate) library(ggplot2) library(grid) library(sf) library(usmap) library(scales) library(Hmisc)  Read in the diseases file diseases&amp;lt;-read.csv(file=&amp;quot;~/GitHub/TidyTuesday/data/2019/2019-12-10/diseases.csv&amp;quot;)  View the dataset diseases %&amp;gt;%dim()  ## [1] 18870 6  The diseases dataset contains 18870 rows and 6 columns</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making A Website With RStudio: The Blogdown Package</title>
      <link>/post/making-a-static-website-using-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-a-static-website-using-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the first post of my blogdown blog! Although I started writing this post in November 2019, it&amp;rsquo;s still been in the drafts as of currently June 2020 &amp;#128517;. I figured the debut post would be best dedicated to sharing my personal experience of using this package as an R user with little to no background in web development.
Before starting a page, it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to have some idea of the difference between static websites vs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>